# Janice T. Johnson

48

484-744-2643

0

jmtj.johnson@gmail.com

in

LinkedIn-janicejohnson

#### **SOFT SKILLS**

Effective Communication Leadership & Collaboration Empathy Human Center Design Problem Solving Critical Thinking

## HARD SKILLS

User Research
User Personas
Prototyping
Wireframes
User Testing
Web Design
Presentations
Digital Data Analytics
Digital Marketing

## **TOOLS**

Figma
Adobe Analytics
Marvel
HTML/CSS

#### CERTIFICATIONS

**Adobe Analytics** Business Practitioner Certified Expert

**Adobe Campaign** Business Practitioner Certified Expert

**HubSpot** Inbound Marketing **seoClarity** Certified User

#### Solution Consultant - Passionate about continuous improvement

I am passionate about applying my digital data and marketing experience with my creativity, empathy, and solution-finding mindset into my work. I continuously seek to create better user experiences for everyone, everywhere.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

January 2017 - April 2022

DIGITAL DATA LEADER

Vanguard, Malvern, PA

- Lead digital measurement strategy to ensure quality insights on audience engagement of
  web, social, email and paid media. Collaborate with business partners to define KPIs,
  ensure marketing technologies have the necessary integrations, and apply best practices.
- Head a data and technology team creating lead generation solutions to advance our
  digital transformation of engagement scoring and data integrations for CRM, web and
  email until the enterprise marketing technology updates are fully implemented.
- **Lead division collaboration** on enterprise global solutions for marketing technologies to ensure the department's marketing transformation needs are being met.
- Developed strategy and led the execution of a tailored curriculum for the department's
   Analytical Learning & Development program to increase analytical acumen, including Test
   & Learn Class, Adobe Analytics Workshop, Foundational & Insights Dashboards
   Workshops, and weekly Office Hours.

#### **OUTCOMES:**

- Lead development of new integrated Campaign Meta Data system across channels and operating systems, allowing analysts easier access to deeper insights.
- Grew an analytics team from one to four members in less than a year. Hired and trained two new digital analysts. They were fully successful and consistently receive positive feedback on the value they provided to their partners in the department.
- Created strategy and led development of integrated dashboards to enable department members and business partners to easily access insights to marketing qualified leads and to make data-driven decisions.
- Developed strategy and led the execution of a tailored curriculum for the department's
   Analytical Learning & Development program to increase analytical acumen, including Test
   & Learn Class, Adobe Analytics Workshop, Foundational & Insights Dashboards
   Workshops, and weekly Office Hours.

July 2016 - January 2017

### **Digital Marketing Consultant**

Wunderman

• Head of a global email team executing 40-70 deliveries per week in multiple languages for a global travel industry leader using Adobe Campaign.

November 2015 – June 2016

#### **Solutions Consultant**

Lima Consulting Group

Partnered with clients to deliver analytics, SEO, and campaign implementation.
 Responsibilities included creating analysis and insights reports with recommendations of content to publish based on research, seasonality, and past results; developing and implementing inbound marketing campaigns to attract potential clients.

## **EDUCATION**

University of Notre Dame,

BBS, Management Information Systems

Career Foundry, UX Design; Web Development

Andersen Consulting Professional Training over 500 hours November 2013 – October 2015 Digital Marketing Specialist

**KBM Group** 

Managed multiple clients' email marketing campaigns. Responsibilities included writing HTML for email, creating and implementing test campaigns, and managing live deployments.

- Reverse-engineered a new client's existing Responsys campaign for deployment and
  established more efficient methods for future campaigns. There was no documentation
  on how the complex campaign initially functioned. The campaign used over 90 driving
  HTML templates to display 200+ monthly offer modules across 5 languages and was
  driven by a distribution list of over 8 million records.
- Transformed the campaign process with a design team to reduce the number of templates to 8 and still accommodate the 5 languages and 200+ offer modules using supplemental tables and dynamic content.

#### **OUTCOMES:**

- Reverse-engineered a new client's existing Responsys campaign for deployment and
  established more efficient methods for future campaigns. There was no documentation
  on how the complex campaign initially functioned. The campaign used over 90 driving
  HTML templates to display 200+ monthly offer modules across 5 languages and was
  driven by a distribution list of over 8 million records.
- Transformed the campaign process with a design team to reduce the number of templates to 8 and still accommodate the 5 languages and 200+ offer modules using supplemental tables and dynamic content. Converted client's campaign from Responsys 5 to 6.

January 2009 – August 2013 Email Campaign Strategist

SEI

- Executed advanced email campaign planning and operations; implemented email best practices; ensured clear content and layout; resolved application issues; provided support and training for each of the business units; HTML and basic Photoshop editing.
- Managed the marketing email service application, Responsys, for SEI Corporate and its 5 business groups across a global market.

# VOLUNTEER LEADERSHIP ROLES

Eighteen years in active volunteer leadership positions in five organizations:

Advancement Chairperson | Cub Scout Pack 231 - Royersford, PA

Email Specialist | DMAX Foundation - Philadelphia, PA

**Board Member, Producer, Director** | Spring-Ford Community Theatre - Royersford, PA

Organization Co-Chair; Committee Chair; Fundraiser Chair; Decorating Chair | Spring-Ford Post Prom - Royersford, PA

**President, Vice President, Yearbook and Various Committee Chairs** | Brooke Elementary Home & School Association - Royersford, PA

Advancement Chairperson | Cub Scout Pack 231 - Royersford, PA